Charles Wu

User Experience Designer/Engineer

charleswu.ca	
hi@charleswu.ca	\checkmark
(+1) 647-767-6126	

Summary

Digital user experience designer with 7 years of experience. Has an engineering background and worked as a developer before transitioning into UX. Focused on discovering user-problems, and designing & iterating on solutions to build impactful products.

Skills

Product Strategy
Design Systems
User Research

Responsive & Accessible Design

HTML, CSS, JS (React)
Git, Python

Tools

Figma, Sketch, Adobe Xd Invision, Axure Ilustrator Photoshop After Effects VSCode Command Line Interface

Experience

UX Engineer | Highline Beta

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

Highline Beta is a startup that builds new ventures in partnership with corporations. I was responsible for managing, designing, and developing projects on several ventures, working with stakeholders, directors, engineers, designers, and end-users.

- Analyzed Female Funder traffic metrics and redesigned the site, which increased user engagement and conversion rates.
- Created Highline Beta's design system, increasing the design & development team's consistency and efficiency.
- Conducted user research to validate solutions for a new venture in the CPG industry. Coordinated with directors to define growth targets and customer experience. Iterated & implemented designs, exponentially growing the monthly customer base.
- Designed and built the 100+ Accelerator site in React, which increased content clarity, branding, site metrics, SEO ratings, site accessibility, and mobile responsiveness.

UX Consultant | Freelance 2018 - Present

I provided UX expertise & services to startups, working closely with founders to increase metrics and determine business needs.

- Researched and defined user needs to build a supply-chain/logistics app. Created the style guide, information architecture, and prototypes to present to potential investors.
- Planned and deployed software systems for e-commerce companies. Built and optimized sites for SEO, and iterated on ads to reduce customer-acquisition-costs.

Senior UX Developer | CareerJSM

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

CareerJSM is a software startup that helps users find jobs with online tools & resources. I managed feature designs and user testing.

- Mentored team members and led the company in best practices for UX through presentations and documentation.
- Implemented accessibility and responsiveness standards across the platform, by conducting audits and adding automated testing.
- Facilitated design sprints, which led to the creation/redesign of 2 features that improved user engagement and value.
- Developed features with 2 other engineers using EmberJS, HTML/SCSS, and PostgreSQL.

UX Developer | DIVE Networks

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

DIVE Networks is a startup that provides a feed of real-time news for companies. I led feature design, testing, and optimization.

- Researched environmental factors to optimize readability, creating standards and requirements for design components.
- Hosted UX training sessions for the company, enabling engineering and product teams better design for customers.
- Developed an automation script to detect visual bugs, increasing product quality and development efficiency.

UX Designer | McKinsey Digital, McKinsey & Company

Summer 2014

- Created designs that visualized complex data, which highlighted insights and increased reading fluency.
- Successfully pitched products to stakeholders on with interactive prototypes (built with Framer JS).

UX Designer & iOS Developer | Ash City (acquired by alphabroder)

Spring 2013

Ash City was a producer and distributor of commercial apparel. I was responsible for the design and development of their debut iOS app.

• Researched and defined product goals for the app in order to increase sale volume. Independently designed, developed, and iterated on the app while presenting progress to management. Completed project within 4 months, increasing overall sales by 10+%.

Education